Guide to the Kappa Kappa Gamma. Delta Beta chapter records, 1930-1981
Duke University. University Archives
Kappa Kappa Gamma. Delta Beta chapter records 1930-1981
Duke University. University Archives
Kappa Kappa Gamma. Delta Beta chapter.
1.3 linear feet Extent: 1,300 Items
This collection contains materials from the Delta Beta chapter of Kappa Kappa Gamma fraternity from 1930-1981. The Delta Beta chapter was established at Duke University in 1930 as a social group for women students. Types of material include correspondence, miscellaneous notes, minutes, bylaws, photographs, and printed materials. Major subjects include student life at Duke University, establishing a fraternal organization, pledging, initiation, community service activities, social activities, songs, general governance, leadership, and public relations.
UA.31.22.0001
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Kappa Kappa Gamma. Delta Beta chapter records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1981, 1985, 1992.
Historical Note
From: http://www.kappakappagamma.org/
Kappa Kappa Gamma Fraternity, a social group for women college students, was founded at Monmouth College in Monmouth, Illinois on October 13, 1870 when six young college women marched into the central campus chapel with golden keys in their hair. Today the Kappa Kappa Gamma symbols are the golden key, the fleur-de-lis and the coat of arms, all representing friendship rooted in a tradition of high standards.
Since its founding, Kappa has grown to more than 128 undergraduate chapters and over 350 alumnae associations worldwide. Kappa Kappa Gamma headquarters, located in Columbus, Ohio, sets community service, membership, and other standards for all Kappa Kappa Gamma chapters. Chapters are visited annually by traveling consultants to check on general compliance with national standards and progress toward goals. Kappa Kappa Gamma's priorities are scholarship and academic achievement, leadership, and community service opportunities for its members.
The Delta Beta chapter of Kappa Kappa Gamma was established at Duke University in 1930. The first Delta Beta chapter meeting was held at the Washington Duke Hotel in Durham, N.C. on October 25, 1930. At that meeting, the first officers were appointed: Erma Williams (President), Katherine Davies (Marshall), Elizabeth Craven (Recording Secretary), Dorothy Leary (Corresponding Secretary), Mildred Guthrie (Registrar), Louise Sellars (Treasurer), and Martha Haure (Correspondent to The Key). The meeting opened with a devotional reading and prayer of the Gamma Xi chapter (University of California, Los Angeles). The first women to pledge to the Delta Beta chapter were: Kathryn Brownlee, Harriet E. Doster, Lillean Hilbert, Martha Kindel, Betty Knight, Frances Lawrence, Dorothy Sharp, Elaine Tenney, Barbara F. Whitmer, and Alice Wooten. They were officially inducted on October 25, 1930.
Some of the issues covered in the first meetings were rushing requirements, alumnae dues, and duties of officers. Other early meetings were guided by a representative from the Lambda chapter at the University of Akron (Ohio) and discussed establishing a study hall, grade improvement of pledges, and sending a delegate to a national Panhellenic conference. The Delta Beta chapter is governed by the Panhellenic Association at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Contains meeting agenda and minutes, pledge programs, constitutions and bylaws, general governance materials, miscellaneous notes, photographs, songbooks, and printed material relating to Kappa Kappa Gamma women's fraternity and the Delta Beta chapter at Duke University.
Collection Arrangement
Series 1. General social material, 1930-1981.
Series 2. Delta Beta chapter affairs, 1934-1981.
Series 3. Scrapbook, 1983.
Series 4. Printed material.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- History; Duke University -- Societies, etc.; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.; Fraternity songs; Greek letter societies; Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham; Initiations (into trades, societies, etc.); Kappa Kappa Gamma; Women college students -- North Carolina -- Societies and clubs
Related Material
Fraternities and Sororities collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Kay Brownlee scrapbooks, 1930-1933.
University Archives, Duke University.
Duke University. Interfraternity Council. Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Duke University. Panhellenic Council records.
University Archives, Duke University.
University Archives Photograph Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- General social material, 1930-1981., 10 folders
  Includes correspondence between the Delta Beta Chapter, Duke University, and the Kappa Kappa Gamma headquarters, Kappa Kappa Gamma songbooks, pledge books, pledge rolls, notes from a leadership convention, and Delta Beta publications.
  - Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
  - Programming notes, ca 1949-1955 (Box 1)
  - Officer evaluations, ca 1967-1970 (Box 1)
  - Songbooks (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Songbooks (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Pledge book, 1930-1954 (Box 1)
  - Pledge rolls, 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Leadership convention, 1968 (Box 1)
  - The Keyhole, 1963-1964, 1979, 1981 (Box 1)
  - The Keychain, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
- Delta Beta chapter affairs, 1934-1981., 7 folders
  Contains bound volumes of Delta Beta chapter bylaws and minutes from house meetings. Ordered by date.
  - Bylaws, 1934-1958 (Box 1)
  - Bylaws, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Bylaws, 1961, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1930-1936 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1936-1941 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1946-1951 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook, 1983., 11 folders (Box 1)
  This scrapbook contains photographs of activities of the members of Kappa Kappa Gamma. Arranged approximately by date.
- Printed material, 1950-1976., 7 folders
  Contains small handbooks and guides produced by Kappa Kappa Gamma Fraternity headquarters for all chapters.
  - Adventures in Leadership, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Chapter Keystones, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Chronology of Kappa Kappa Gamma Fraternity, 1970-1976, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, Bylaws, Standing Rules, and Policies, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Our Kappa Home, 1950 (Box 1)
  - What every Kappa Should Know, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Pledge handbooks, 1950, 1958, 1962 (Box 1)